truthinengineering.com 2019-05-22

# Audi privacy statement | Audi USA

##### Last Modified January 1, 2019

With regard to data collected from or about your vehicle, the Model Year 2019 Privacy Statement applies to all Model Year 2019 vehicles and newer as well as to any older vehicles if an owner or registered user agrees to the Model Year 2019 Privacy Statement (including all vehicles where an owner or registered user sign up to be a Key User or for Connect PRIME services on or after January 1, 2019). If you own a used vehicle and are unsure which privacy statement applies to you, you may contact us at auditalk@audi.com or by phone, 24 hours a day, at: 1-800-822-AUDI, for more information.

At Audi of America, Inc., an operating division of Volkswagen Group of America, Inc. (“AoA,” “We,” or “Us”), we value your privacy and your desire to know how your information will be handled and used.  To better protect your privacy, we provide this Privacy Statement, which explains our information practices.  This statement applies to information we obtain from and about individuals interacting with AoA and its websites, mobile applications, vehicles, products and services; however, it does not apply to job applicants or AoA employees.

This Statement does not apply to Audi Financial Services (“AFS”) or its products, contracts and related services. AFS has its own privacy statement, which can be found _[here](https://www.audifs.com/Public/PrivacyPolicy)_.

Below we provide a summary of the general information we collect, how we use it and with whom it is shared.  Because we don’t collect all of the information described below in all circumstances, we have separately identified the information that is collected when you choose to purchase or use additional products or services available with your Audi vehicle (such as myAudi, or Audi connect services beyond Connect CARE, which include Connect PRIME, and Connect PLUS).  For more information, please see the detailed sections for each of these services.

If you are a California resident, please view the “Your California Privacy Rights” section of the full privacy statement for more information on your California privacy rights.

**_HIGHLIGHTS_**

**How Do We Collect Information?**

We collect information from and about you from different sources, which include:

  * Information you provide to us directly or when you interact with us
  * Information collected from your vehicle
  * Information from third parties

**What Information Do We Collect?**

The types of information that AoA collects from and about you and your vehicle include:

  * **Information you provide,** such as **** your preferences, **** photographs and other user-generated content, and other materials that you may submit
  * **Vehicle purchase/lease/service information,** such as contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, email) and vehicle purchase or lease information (such as VIN, make, model, year, dealer, date of purchase or lease, purchase/lease price, vehicle equipment, and service history) ****
  * **Vehicle data transmitted from your vehicle** , such as general status data (such as warning lights, upcoming service schedule, fuel level, battery level, tire pressure); service history and fault or trouble codes; ambient data (such as outside temperature and brightness); vehicle performance data; other data about your vehicle including its identification, condition, equipment status, or collision information; vehicle/technology usage data (such as usage of start/stop and remote start technology); driver behavior data (such as vehicle speed, seat belt use, and information about braking habits);  ** _and GPS location data_**
  * **Other information about you and how you interact with us** , such as data gathered by technology when you visit our website or use our mobile applications (such as IP address, browser information, ICCID, device type, app and OS version, etc.), demographic information and product preferences

**This data _, including driver behavior GPS location data_ , will be collected regardless of whether you sign up for or use additional services, described below, and may be used or shared for the purposes described below.**  **However, your connected vehicle may be equipped with a “Privacy Mode” that allows you to control what information is collected from the vehicle, including the ability to discontinue any sharing of vehicle data.   Please see the “Your Choices” section below for more information. **Vehicle models that offer limited connected services from third parties only (such as online traffic and infotainment), but not any remote services from Audi (TT, R8, A3, and Q3 models) are not equipped with Privacy Mode because Audi does not collect data from such vehicles.

If you set up a myAudi account, additional information will be collected, including:

  * Information regarding your myAudi settings, such as preferred Audi dealer, and preferred contact for service notifications
  * Additional data you provide for use of particular applications or for direct communications
  * Additional data you choose to share to help tailor your myAudi account content and services

If you choose to activate optional Audi connect services, including Connect PRIME and Connect PLUS, additional information will be collected, including:

  * Account information, such as billing, settings, personalized services and authentication information
  * Information that you provide when using the Audi connect services, including information you send and information you request
  * Information about your use of Audi connect services, vehicles equipped with Audi connect services, the Audi connect mobile application, and the Audi connect website
  * Information about your interactions with us, our affiliates, or our service or Content Providers (defined below)
  * Spoken data (and any personal data included therein) when using voice command features

If you choose to register a Key User or Authorized Users, which is required in order to use certain Connect PRIME services, we collect additional information provided to identify those users, including:

  * Name
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Login credentials and security PIN

If you choose to register a Key User, the “Audi Service Request” function is automatically enabled as part of Connect CARE. We automatically transmit the technical data (such as vehicle condition data and service-relevant data) for an upcoming service interval of your vehicle to an Audi Dealer in advance.  Registering a Key User will also automatically activate Remote Lock/Unlock services as part of Connect CARE.

If your vehicle is equipped with online “over the air” system update capability, we will also collect software and hardware version and serial numbers of vehicle hardware and use this information to provide online system updates. You will receive a notification in the car that an “over the air” system update is scheduled, and you will be able to confirm the update using your security PIN.

**How Do We Use Your Information?**

We may use your information in a number of ways, including:

  * **To provide you with products and services,** such as **** to provide products and services you may request; support your vehicle, products and services; diagnose, repair and track service and quality issues; communicate with you about your vehicle, products or services; install and configure changes and updates to your services; authenticate users of our products and services; or verify your eligibility for certain programs or benefits ****
  * **For our own internal business purposes** , such as to evaluate the usage, performance and safety of our vehicles, products and services; improve the quality of our vehicles, products and services, and design new products and services; operate the AoA website and digital properties and customize the content; or maintain internal records
  * **For legal, safety or security reasons,** such as to comply with legal requirements; protect the safety, property or rights of AoA, owners, registered users, drivers, passengers or others; or prevent and detect fraud or misuse of the vehicles, products or services
  * **For marketing.   **However, please note that GPS location and driver behavior data will not be used for AoA marketing purposes or shared with unaffiliated third parties to use for their own purposes without your affirmative consent. ****
  * **In an anonymized or aggregated format.**   We may also use any information we collect about you or your vehicle in an anonymized or aggregate manner for any purpose. ****

**With Whom Do We Share Your Information?**

We may share your information with third parties for any purpose described above, including with the following third parties:

  * Within the Volkswagen Group family of companies, which includes parents, corporate affiliates, subsidiaries, business units and other companies that share common ownership, including Audi AG
  * With select business partners for joint business purposes or for their own business purposes
  * With third-party service providers working on behalf of AoA and third party content providers
  * With emergency service providers
  * With your vehicle’s satellite radio and/or wireless service provider
  * With independent, AoA-authorized dealerships
  * As otherwise required by law
  * As authorized with your permission

As you interact with AoA websites, you can provide us information directly if you choose to do so.  Additionally, we may collect certain information from or about you or your vehicle as further described below.

  * **Information you provide to us directly or when you interact with us**.  We collect the information you provide to us directly or when you interact with us, such as when you visit or use this website, use AoA and third party digital properties (including social media sites and sweepstakes microsites), or during other interactions such as product and related events, test drives, surveys, promotion entries, and with our customer call centers.
  * **Information collected from your vehicle**.  We collect information about your vehicle and how you use it, such as information about your vehicle’s performance, status, and GPS location.  We collect this information regardless of which, if any, services you sign up to use.
  * **Information from third parties**.  We receive information about you and your vehicle from third parties such as:

  1. Your independent, AoA-authorized dealership (hereafter, “Audi Dealer”).  Examples of information we receive include vehicle leasing records, vehicle, accessory, and parts sales and service records, and other records provided to us
  2. AoA-authorized sellers of consumer merchandise
  3. Audi Financial Services (“AFS”), an operating unit of Volkswagen Credit, Inc. (if you finance your AoA vehicle purchase or purchase products from AFS)
  4. Third party service and content providers
  5. Other third parties, such as companies that provide or sell lists of potential vehicle purchasers and current owners

We may combine information that we receive from the various sources described in this Privacy Statement, including third-party sources, with personal information and use or disclose it for the purposes identified below.

The types of information that AoA collects about you include:

  * **Information you provide,** such as **** your preferences, **** photographs and other user-generated content, and other materials that you may submit
  * **Vehicle purchase/lease/service information,** such as contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, email) and vehicle purchase, lease or service information (such as VIN, make, model, year, dealer, date of purchase or lease, purchase/lease price, vehicle equipment, and service history) ****
  * **Vehicle data transmitted from your vehicle** , such as general status data(such as warning lights, upcoming service schedule, fuel level, battery level, and tire pressure); service history and fault or trouble codes; ambient data (such as outside temperature and brightness); vehicle performance data and other data about your vehicle including its identification, condition, equipment status, or collision information; vehicle/technology usage data (such as usage of start/stop and remote start technology); driver behavior data (such as vehicle speed, seat belt use, and information about braking habits); ** _  and GPS location data_**
  * **Other Information about you and how you interact with us** , such as data gathered by technology when you visit our website or use our mobile applications (such as IP address, browser information, ICCID, device type, app and OS version, etc.), demographic information and product preferences

If your vehicle is equipped with an Event Data Recorder (“EDR”), crash or near-crash information about the vehicle or driver’s behavior will be recorded in the vehicle.  EDR data are recorded by your vehicle only if a non-trivial crash situation occurs, not under normal driving conditions. For information about your vehicle’s EDR data or other crash or near crash information collected and how we might receive and use it, please see your owner’s manual.

Audi vehicles may be equipped with Audi connect CARE, which does not require any action from you to activate and is automatically enabled and active before purchase or lease. Audi connect CARE cannot be disabled in equipped vehicles, without significantly impacting the impacting the user experience and function of the infotainment system. This plan includes some or all of the following services:

  * Automatic and manual Audi emergency call (in the event of an airbag deployment or if you contact us directly through the ‘SOS’ button to notify us of an emergency, an emergency service center, contracted by AoA, will respond);
  * Stolen vehicle locator (at your request, we will attempt to locate your stolen vehicle in coordination with law enforcement authorities); and
  * Online roadside assistance (non-emergency roadside assistance when requested, including through use of the “wrench” button).
  * Remote Lock/Unlock functions

The Connect CARE plan requires the collection and use of information from you (which may include a phone call to discuss the situation and assistance needed, which is recorded and monitored) and your vehicle (including your vehicle’s GPS location and other vehicle data that will help us get emergency responders to you or help us dispatch appropriate service providers). GPS location data that is collected for the purpose of providing Connect CARE services is only available and used by us upon our receipt of an automatic notification from your vehicle, when the SOS button is pushed or when you request other online roadside services through the “wrench” button.

Although Connect CARE is automatically activated in equipped vehicles, to utilize the Audi Service Request and Remote Lock/Unlock functions of Connect CARE, you must register a “key user.”  The data collection practices around key user registration and Audi Service Request functionality are discussed in separate sections below.

We may use your information in a number of ways, including:

  * **To provide you with products and services,** such as **** to provide products and services you may request; support your vehicle, products and services; diagnose, repair and track service and quality issues; communicate with you about your vehicle, products or services; install and configure changes and updates to your services; authenticate users of our products and services; or verify your eligibility for certain programs or benefits ****
  * **For our own internal business purposes** , such as to evaluate the usage, performance and safety of our vehicles, products and services; improve the quality of our vehicles, products and services and design new products and services; operate the AoA website and digital properties and customize the content; or maintain internal records
  * **For legal, safety or security reasons,** such as to comply with legal requirements; protect the safety, property or rights of AoA, owners, registered users, drivers, passengers or others; or prevent and detect fraud or misuse of the vehicles, products or services
  * **For marketing.   **However, please note that GPS location or driver behavior data will not be used for AoA marketing purposes or shared with unaffiliated third parties to use for their own purposes without your affirmative consent. ****
  * **In an anonymous or aggregated format.**   We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner for any purpose.

We may share your information (a) within the Volkswagen Group family of companies, which includes parents, corporate affiliates, subsidiaries, business units and other companies that share common ownership, including Audi AG; (b) with third-party service providers working on behalf of AoA (such as advertising agencies and third parties that provide marketing services, marketing research, and other analytics for marketing purposes) and third party content providers; and (c) Audi Dealers for sales, leasing, and customer service purposes, such as responding to quote requests, vehicle diagnosis, maintenance and repair, scheduling service appointments, and contacting you and providing the requested services. Some of our service providers, including Audi AG, are located outside of the United States.

We also share your information with emergency responders and service providers (such as police, ambulance providers, and towing providers) and law enforcement for purposes of offering Connect CARE.

We also share information with your vehicle’s satellite radio and/or wireless service provider, if applicable, to enable those service providers to contact you with important information about your vehicle’s satellite or wireless services and for their own marketing purposes.

With your express permission, we also will share your information with selected third parties you choose, to enable services that use your information but are not provided directly by AoA. These services could include, but are not limited to, remote package and fuel delivery, or usage-based insurance or tolling pricing, or other mobility-based services.

In addition, we may share your information with third parties, law enforcement or other government agencies to comply with law or legal requirements; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; and to protect our rights and the property or safety of our users or third-parties. We also may disclose information about you and your vehicle when we have reason to believe that someone is causing injury to or interference with our rights or property, other users of the websites or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities.

If we or some or all of our assets are acquired by another company, including through a sale in connection with bankruptcy, we will share the information that we hold with that company.

We also share your information with other carefully selected companies with whom we may partner to provide you with information about products or services we think may be of interest to you. 

We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

Most Audi vehicles are equipped with technology that tracks, and shares with AoA, information about the vehicle as described above, including numerous data points about the vehicle’s usage, performance, safety, status, and **_GPS location_**.  AoA uses and shares this information for the purposes described above.

Your vehicle may be equipped with a “Privacy Mode” that allows you to control what information is collected from the vehicle, including the ability to discontinue any sharing of vehicle data except for emergency call purposes. Please see the “Audi Connect” or “Data Privacy” sections of the owner’s manual for your vehicle to determine if your vehicle has Privacy Mode. You may also find a list of vehicle models equipped with privacy mode **_[here](https://www.audiusa.com/content/dam/audiusa/Innovation/Intelligence/Intelligence_Audi_Connect/Audi-connect-Vehicles-equipped-with-Privacy-Mode_9.10.2018.pdf)_**.  Please note that disabling the data sharing capabilities will inhibit AoA’s ability to provide you with Audi connect services and other functionalities. Please see your owner’s manual for a description of what services will be disrupted and what will still be available when privacy mode is enabled. Vehicle models that offer limited connected services from third parties only (such as online traffic and infotainment), but not any remote services from Audi (TT, R8, A3, and Q3 models) are not equipped with Privacy Mode because Audi does not collect data from such vehicles.

To opt-out of receiving promotional email messages from us, please click on the "Unsubscribe" link contained at the bottom of each email.

##### _Online Advertising_

To provide you with a more relevant and interesting experience, AoA may work with third party companies to display ads or customize the content of the AoA digital properties.  These companies may use cookies (a small text file), pixels, tags, or similar technologies that are placed in browsers to gather information about your visits to an AoA digital property, as well as your visits elsewhere on the Internet.  These companies use this information to provide you with more relevant advertising known as interest-based advertising. Some of these companies may be participants in the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA"). The DAA offers a choice mechanism with respect to certain types of data collection and use. We adhere to the DAA’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. Visit www.aboutads.info to exercise choice with respect to participants of the DAA or click on the AboutAds icon on an AoA advertisement and follow the instructions on how to opt out. If you change computers, devices, or browsers, use multiple computers, devices, or browsers, or delete your cookies, you may need to repeat this process for each computer, device, or browser. Opting out of interest-based advertising will not opt you out of all advertising, but rather only interest-based advertising from AoA or its agents or representatives.

To opt-out of receiving promotional email messages from us, please click on the "Unsubscribe" link contained at the bottom of each email.

The AoA websites also collect information, via cookies, web beacons, pixels, tags or other tracking technologies, such as your Internet Service Provider and IP address, the date and time you access the AoA website, the pages you have accessed while visiting the AoA website, and the Internet address from which you accessed the AoA website. Some cookies exist only during a single session and some are persistent over multiple sessions over time.  We use these technologies to remember user preferences, maximize the performance of our website and services, provide you with offers that may be of interest to you, measure the effectiveness of our email campaigns and to personalize online content.

Some browsers have incorporated Do Not Track (“DNT”) preferences. Most of these features, when turned on, send signals to the website you are visiting that you do not wish to have information about your online searching and browsing activities collected and used.  As there is not yet a common agreement about how to interpret DNT signals, we do not honor DNT signals from website browsers at this time.  However, you may refuse or delete cookies.  If you refuse or delete cookies, some of our website functionality may be impaired.  Please refer to your browser’s Help instructions to learn more about how to manage cookies and the use of other tracking technologies.

In addition to mobile applications designed to allow you to use your myAudi or Audi connect services, AoA may have mobile applications that you can download to your mobile device or vehicle (“AoA Applications”). When you download an AoA Application, there may be an opportunity for you to provide us with or for us to obtain information about you or your vehicle. Each AoA Application will display a separate Privacy Statement that will inform you about how any new or different information shared via the application will be handled.  Otherwise, information collected via AoA Applications will be the information identified above and will be used and shared as stated in this Privacy Statement.

Through the Infotainment system, AoA may also offer applications developed by third parties (“3rd Party Application”). When you download a 3rd Party Application to your mobile device or vehicle, the 3rd Party Application may collect information about you or your vehicle in connection with your download or use of that application. AoA is not responsible for the collection or use of information by 3rd Party Applications. We recommend that you carefully review the privacy statement of each 3rd Party Application prior to downloading or using them.

AoA does not knowingly collect information from visitors under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.  For questions or additional information, see the “Contact Us” section below.

The AoA websites may contain links to other websites, including social networks, advertisers, Audi Dealer websites, Audi Financial Services websites, other Volkswagen Group websites, including websites operated by Audi AG, and websites belonging to other third parties. Some of these sites may share a similar “look and feel” to the AoA websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements provided by other websites before you provide information to them.

AoA maintains reasonable safeguards to protect your information.  Some services, including Audi connect services, may involve the transmission of voice and data from your Audi vehicle over wireless and cellular telephone networks and therefore, we cannot guarantee the privacy and security of conversations or data transmitted to and from your Audi vehicle.

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Statement by updating this page and by displaying the date of the last update at the top of the page. We encourage you periodically to check this site to learn about the information we collect, use, and share. Your continued use of any of the AoA websites, products or services affirms your agreement to such changes.

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request information from AoA regarding the manner in which AoA shares certain categories of your personal information with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. California law provides that you have the right to submit a request to AoA at its designated address and receive the following information:

  * The categories of information AoA disclosed to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year; and
  * The names and addresses of third parties that received such information, or if the nature of their business cannot be determined from the name, then examples of the products or services marketed.

You are entitled to receive a copy of this information in a standardized format and the information will not be specific to you individually. You may make such a request by emailing auditalk@audi.com or by contacting us via the contact information below. 

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement, please email us at: [auditalk@audi.com](mailto:auditalk@audi.com).

You may also contact us by phone, 24 hours a day, at: 1-800-822-AUDI.

And by mail at:

Audi Customer Experience Center  
3800 Hamlin Road  
Auburn Hills, MI 48326

##### **If You Create a myAudi Account**

You can choose to create a myAudi account to access and use AoA personalized services, applications and programs relating to your vehicle.  In addition to the information practices described in the AoA Full Privacy Statement, this statement describes how we collect, use and share your information during registration and use of your myAudi account and the applications, program and services available through myAudi.  You can create a myAudi account without choosing to use Audi connect services.  If you also choose to utilize Audi connect services, we have provided additional information below about information collection, use and sharing for those services.

In addition, you may choose to access your Audi Financial Services (AFS) account through your myAudi portal.  If you do so, the details of your financial transactions (e.g. account balance, automatic payments, bank account information) will not be shared with AoA, its affiliated entities or the third parties identified in this Privacy Statement. Such information will be used strictly in accordance with the AFS Privacy Statement available _[here](https://www.audifs.com/Public/PrivacyPolicy)_.  Information shared between Audi and AFS will be limited to general vehicle purchase information such as VIN, make, model, year, dealer, date of purchase or lease, purchase/lease price, vehicle equipment, and service history—even if you choose to access your AFS account through your myAudi portal.

In addition to the general information identified above, we collect the information that you provide in your myAudi account in the course of or subsequent to registration and verification. This includes:

  * Data that you provide when setting up a myAudi Account, such as gender, salutation, preferred language, usernames and passwords
  * Data regarding your personalized settings for your Audi connect services accessed through you myAudi account, such as preferred Audi partners, preferences for using e-mail, mailing address or text messages for sending service or application function notifications, vehicle catalogues, newsletter or other direct communications
  * Additional data you choose to share to help tailor your myAudi account content and services

In addition to the uses identified above, we use the information provided through your myAudi account registration and use to: activate the account; allow you to access your myAudi account; allow you to use the available applications, services and programs available through your myAudi account; perform desired customer services; and maintain information relevant to your myAudi account. We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

You can register an Audi vehicle in your myAudi account by entering and saving your vehicle identification number (“VIN”). The VIN is required to access and use certain applications in your vehicle and to use the vehicle management application in your myAudi account.  By using the vehicle management application, your vehicle's equipment details can be automatically populated by entering your vehicle identification number.

The data you enter into your myAudi account are saved and made available to your registered vehicle on demand. We save the data until you delete it from your myAudi Account or you delete your myAudi Account.

##### **If You Choose to Use Audi connect Services**

You can choose to use your myAudi account to access and use available Audi connect services, which include Connect PRIME and Connect PLUS (Connect CARE is automatically provided).  Certain vehicles may be equipped with Audi connect CARE, which does not require any action from you to activate and is automatically enabled and active before purchase or lease. Connect CARE data collection and use practices were discussed above.  If you activate a free trial or paid subscription to Audi connect services, additional information will be collected.  In addition to the information identified in the full AoA Privacy Statement above, we collect, use, and share information about you and your registered Audi vehicle during your free trial or paid subscription services available through Audi connect.  Some Audi connect vehicles are not equipped to offer all of the Audi connect services mentioned in this Privacy Statement.  To find out what services are available in your vehicle, see www.audiusa.com/audiconnect.

The Audi connect services include offerings from various third-party content providers, such as Google, Twitter, etc. (“Content Provider”).  AoA does not create or control the content offered by these Content Providers.  The Content Providers are exclusively responsible for the content and the availability of the content accessible through Audi connect.  However, AoA does collect and share certain information with these Content Providers in order for you to receive the content requested.  For a complete list of the Audi connect Content Providers and their respective contact information, please see “Content Providers” below.

For complete Audi connect Terms of Service please click _[here](https://www.audiusa.com/content/dam/audiusa/Innovation/Intelligence/Intelligence_Audi_Connect/Audi_connect_ToS_Jan_4_2016.pdf)_.

Please note that through Audi connect services, including Connect PLUS, you can purchase additional services or offerings from us or other third parties.  Certain services or offerings from third parties will be subject to their Terms of Service and Privacy Statement, not ours.  This includes Wi-Fi hotspot service, provided by a wireless carrier that contracts directly with you.  In the course of providing wireless services, the provider may collect information about you, your Audi vehicle, and your use of Audi connect services, including information that allows the provider to determine the location of your vehicle.  The provider’s collection, use, and sharing of the information it collects is governed by its own privacy policy, not ours.  You should read the privacy policy that your wireless provider has made available to you because the provider’s practices may differ from ours.  If you are not the subscriber for this vehicle’s Audi connect services, you should ask the vehicle’s subscriber to tell you about any third party providers contracting directly with the subscriber, including which carrier is providing this vehicle’s wireless services.

In addition to the general information from and about you or your vehicle identified in the full AoA Privacy Statement and myAudi information above, when you set up and use Audi connect services, additional information will be collected, including:

  * Account information, such as billing, settings, personalized services and authentication information
  * Information that you provide when using the Audi connect services, including information you send and information you request
  * Information about your use of Audi connect services, vehicles equipped with Audi connect services, the Audi connect mobile application, and the Audi connect website
  * Information about your interactions with us, our affiliates, or our service or Content Providers
  * Voice command data (including any personal data included therein) combined with GPS location data, for the purpose of providing the requested service and to improve the voice command capabilities

If you set up and use Audi connect services, and your car is equipped with online voice command, you will be provided an opportunity in your vehicle to acknowledge and accept these conditions before the online "voice command" function can be used.

Please note that the information stored in your Audi vehicle may be accessible to others who use your Audi vehicle or mobile device, and thus may be deleted, altered, or transferred.  Please see your vehicle’s owner’s manual for information about how to remove the information stored in your Audi vehicle.

We do not store the content of any messages (such as social media messages) that you transmit or access through Audi connect and we do not access or retain information about the locations associated with any information requests (such as information feeds, travel information) that you submit through Audi connect, other than information requests for location based services.

In addition to the entities identified in the full AoA Privacy Statement above, we share information collected through use of Audi connect services with the third-party Content Providers identified below.  Information about how Content Providers use and share information associated with your use of Audi connect services is available at the Content Providers’ websites.

The following is a list of the current Audi connect Content Providers and their respective websites and contact information. This list is subject to change without notice.

**Content Providers**

At present, the following third-party Content Providers offer services via Audi connect:

  * Point-of-interest searching (POI), including voice control, navigation with Google Earth images : Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA – www.google.com
  * Twitter: Twitter Inc. 795 Folsom Street, Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA – www.twitter.com
  * News: www.afp.com, www.npr.com and any other RSS feed providers that you may choose to add;
  * City events: Wcities.com, Inc., 512 2nd Street Second Floor, San Francisco , CA 94107, USA – www.wcities.com;
  * Traffic information: HERE Global B.V., Kennedyplein 222 -226, 5611 ZT Eindhoven, The Netherlands
  * Parking information: Parkopedia Limited,  232 Sladepool Farm Road, Birmingham, West Midlands, B14 5EE – _[www.parkopedia.com](http://www.parkopedia.com/)_
  * Fuel price information: OPISNAVX c/o IHS, 18 rue du Quatre Septembre, 75002 Paris, France - www.opisnavx.com/
  * Flight information: FlightStats, Inc., 522 SW 5th Avenue, Suite 200, Portland, OR 97204, USA – www.flightstats-inc.com
  * Traffic light information: Traffic Technology Services, Inc., 17933 NW Evergreen Pkwy #240, Beaverton, OR 97006 – www.traffictechservices.com
  * Weather:  MeteoGroup Ltd., 292 Vauxhall Bridge Road, London SW1V 1AE - www.meteogroup.com

In addition to the general purposes described above, we use the information generated in association with your use of Audi connect services to process your specific requests for Audi connect services.

We use the information provided to register a Key User and Authorized Users to authenticate the users and provide them with requested Audi connect services.

We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

##### **If You Choose to Register a Key User**

You must create a myAudi account and register a “Key User” to access and use certain Connect CARE services, such as Audi Service Requests and Remote Lock & Unlock, and certain Connect PRIME services, such as Curfew Alerts, Geofencing Alerts, Speed Alerts, Valet Alerts, Parking Position, and Vehicle Status Report.  You can also register other “Authorized Users” to allow them to access and use some of these Audi connect services.

Designating and activating a Key User or Authorized User requires the collection of additional information about those users, including:

  * Name
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Login credential and PIN

At the time of Key User Registration, the “Audi Service Request” function is activated as part of Connect CARE.  We use the information provided in association with an Audi Service Request to evaluate your service needs and remind you to schedule a service appointment as indicated in your contact preferences. If your contact preferences include a preferred Audi Dealer or service center, we will also share information about your vehicle with your preferred Audi Dealer or service center, or another Audi Dealer or service center if you do not have a preferred one. An Audi service representative may contact you via phone, email or letter to schedule a service appointment.  Your preferred Audi Dealer may also contact you via phone, email or letter to schedule a service appointment, and can also access this data for the purpose of preparing for and executing the service appointment.

To opt-out of the Audi Service Request feature, please log in to your myAudi account.

##### Last Modified January 1, 2019

With regard to data collected from or about your vehicle, the Model Year 2018 Privacy Statement applies to Model Year 2018 vehicles and older, unless a more specific privacy statement applies to an individual model or if an owner or registered user agrees to the Model Year 2019 Privacy Statement.  The Model Year 2019 Privacy Statement will apply to all Model Year 2018 or older vehicles where an owner or registered user signed up to be a Key User or for Connect PRIME services on or after January 1, 2019. If you own a used vehicle and are unsure which privacy statement applies to you, you may contact us at [auditalk@audi.com](mailto:auditalk@audi.com) or by phone, 24 hours a day, at: 1-800-822-AUDI, for more information.

At Audi of America, Inc., an operating division of Volkswagen Group of America, Inc. (“AoA” “We” or “Us”), we value your privacy and your desire to know how your information will be handled and used.  To better protect your privacy we provide this Privacy Statement, which explains our information practices.  This statement applies to information we obtain from and about individuals interacting with AoA and its websites, vehicles, products and services, however, it does not apply to job applicants or AoA employees.

**This Statement does not apply to Audi Financial Services (“AFS”) or its products, contracts and related services. AFS has its own privacy statement, which can be found _[here](https://www.audifs.com/Public/PrivacyPolicy)_.**

Below we provide a summary of the general information we collect, how we use it and with whom it is shared.  Because we don’t collect all of the information described below in all circumstances, we have separately identified the information that is collected when you choose to purchase or use additional products or services available with your Audi vehicle (such as myAudi, or Audi connect services beyond Connect CARE, which include Connect PRIME, and Connect PLUS).  For more information, please see the detailed sections for each of these services.

**_HIGHLIGHTS_**

**What Information Do We Collect?**

The types of information that AoA collects from and about you and your vehicle include:

  * contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, email)
  * information you provide directly to us
  * vehicle purchase or lease information (such as VIN, make, model, year, dealer, date of purchase or lease, purchase/lease price, vehicle equipment, and service history)
  * vehicle data (such as general status data--warning lights, upcoming service schedule, fuel level, battery level, tire pressure; service history and fault or trouble codes; ambient data -- outside temperature and brightness; vehicle performance data; and other data about your vehicle including its identification, condition, equipment status, or collision information)
  * vehicle/technology usage data (such as usage of start/stop and remote start technology)
  * **_GPS location data when needed for Connect CARE services or as required by law_**
  * photographs and other user-generated content such as materials that you may submit for contests or sweepstakes
  * data gathered by technology when you visit our website

If you set up a myAudi account, additional information will be collected, including:

  * information regarding your myAudi settings, such as preferred Audi dealer, and preferred contact for service notifications
  * additional data you provide for use of particular applications or for direct communications
  * additional data you choose to share to help tailor your myAudi account content and services

If you choose to activate optional Audi connect services, including Connect PRIME and Connect PLUS, additional information will be collected, including:

  * account information, such as billing, settings, personalized services and authentication information
  * information that you provide when using the Audi connect services, including information you send and information you request
  * information about your use of Audi connect services, vehicles equipped with Audi connect services, the Audi connect mobile application, and the Audi connect website
  * information about your interactions with us, our affiliates, or our Service or Content Providers
  * spoken data (and any personal data included therein) when using voice command features
  * **_GPS location data for services, such as Geofence, Map Update, Parking Position, Speed Alert, Valet Alert, Traffic Information, Local Hazard Alerts, Weather and Travel Destinations_**
  * **_driving behavior information for services, such as speed for Speed Alert, Local Hazard Alert, Online Traffic Signs, and Valet Alert_**

If you choose to register a Key User or Authorized Users, required in order to use certain Connect PRIME services, we collect additional information provided to identify those users, including:

  * name
  * date of birth
  * email address
  * login credentials and security PIN

If you choose to register a Key User, the “Audi Service Request” function is automatically enabled as part of Connect CARE. We automatically transmit the technical data required (such as vehicle condition data and service-relevant data) for an upcoming service interval of your vehicle to your dealer in advance.

If you use a mobile device to activate or access services, we may collect information about your specific mobile device (such as ICCID, device type, app version and OS version). 

If your vehicle is equipped with online “over the air” system update capability, we will also collect software and hardware version and serial numbers of vehicle hardware and use this information to provide online system updates. You will receive a notification in the car that an “over the air” system update is scheduled, and you will be able to confirm the update using your security PIN.

**How Do We Use Your Information?**

We may use your information in a number of ways, including:

  * to provide the products and services you have purchased or requested
  * to support your vehicle, products and services
  * to diagnose, repair and track service and quality issues
  * to communicate with you about your vehicle, products or services
  * to install and configure changes and updates to your services
  * to authenticate users of our products and services
  * to evaluate the performance and safety of our vehicles, products and services
  * to improve the quality of our vehicles, products and services
  * to operate the AoA website and digital properties and customize the content
  * to verify your eligibility for certain programs or benefits
  * to comply with legal requirements
  * to protect the safety, property or rights of AoA, owners, registered users, drivers, passengers or others
  * to prevent and detect fraud or misuse of the vehicles, products or services
  * to maintain internal records
  * for marketing purposes

**With Whom Do We Share Your Information?**

We may share your information, including: ****

  * within the Volkswagen Group family of companies, which includes parents, corporate affiliates, subsidiaries, business units and other companies that share common ownership, including Audi AG
  * with select business partners
  * with third-party service providers working on behalf of AoA and third party content providers
  * with emergency service providers
  * with your vehicle’s satellite radio and/or wireless service provider
  * with independent, AoA-authorized dealerships
  * as otherwise required by law
  * as authorized with your express permission

We may also use or share your information (including all of the information outlined in this Privacy Statement for other services, such as myAudi or Audi connect) in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

As you interact with AoA websites, you can provide us information directly if you choose to do so.  Additionally, we may collect certain information from or about you or your vehicle as further described below.

You may provide us with information about you or your vehicle through a number of sources: this website, information directly from your vehicle, use of other Audi products or services (e.g. myAudi, Audi connect or Audi connect e-tron), use of Audi and third party digital properties (including social media sites and sweepstakes microsites), product and related events, test drives, surveys, social media platforms, promotion entries and our customer call centers.  We receive information about you and your vehicle through vehicle leasing records, vehicle, accessory, and parts sales and service records, and other records, provided to us directly by your independent, AoA-authorized dealership (hereafter, “Audi Dealer”), or our third-party service providers.  If you register for and receive services through a myAudi account, we also receive information about your preferred Audi Dealer, any interests you elect to share, and your account preferences and settings.  If you sign up for AoA’s connected services or Audi connect e-tron, we also receive directly from your vehicle, information about your vehicle, including its performance, status and location, and driving behavior and Key User or Authorized Users designations and information. 

In addition to information we obtain from Audi Dealers and connected services that you may choose to use, we also may obtain information about you and your vehicle from AoA-authorized sellers of consumer merchandise, Audi Financial Services (“AFS”), an operating unit of Volkswagen Credit, Inc., (if you finance your AoA vehicle purchase or purchase products from AFS) and other sources such as companies that provide or sell lists of potential vehicle purchasers and current owners.  We may combine information that we receive from the various sources described in this Privacy Statement, including third-party sources, with personal information and use it for the purposes identified below.

The types of information that AoA collects about you include:

  * contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, email)
  * information you provide directly to us
  * vehicle purchase or lease information (such as VIN, make, model, year, dealer, date of purchase or lease, purchase/lease price, vehicle equipment, and service history)
  * vehicle data (such as general status data--warning lights, upcoming service schedule, fuel level, battery level, tire pressure, service history and fault or trouble codes; ambient data -- outside temperature and brightness; vehicle performance data; and other data about your vehicle including its identification, condition, equipment status, or collision information)
  * vehicle/technology usage data (such as usage of start/stop and remote start technology)
  * **_GPS location data when needed for Connect CARE services or as required by law_**
  * photographs and other user-generated content such as materials that you may submit for contests or sweepstakes
  * data gathered by technology when you visit our website

If you use a mobile device to activate or access services, we may collect information about your specific mobile device (such as ICCID, device type, app version and OS version). .

If your vehicle is equipped with an Event Data Recorder (“EDR”) crash or near-crash information about the vehicle or driver’s behavior will be recorded in the vehicle.  EDR data are recorded by your vehicle only if a non-trivial crash situation occurs, not under normal driving conditions.

For information about your vehicle’s EDR data or other crash or near crash information collected and how we might receive and use it, please see your owner’s manual.

Audi vehicles may be equipped with Audi Connect CARE which does not require any action from you to activate and is automatically enabled and active before purchase or lease. Audi connect CARE cannot be disabled in equipped vehicles. This plan includes:

  * automatic and manual Audi emergency call (in the event of an airbag deployment or if you contact us directly through the ‘SOS’ button to notify us of an emergency, an emergency service center, contracted by AoA, will respond);
  * stolen vehicle locator (at your request, we will attempt to locate your stolen vehicle in coordination with law enforcement authorities); and
  * online roadside assistance (non-emergency roadside assistance when requested, including through use of the “wrench” button).

The Connect CARE plan requires the collection and use of information from you (which may include a phone call to discuss the situation and assistance needed, **_which is recorded and monitored_** ) and your vehicle (including **_your vehicle’s GPS location_** and other vehicle data that will help us get emergency responders to you or help us dispatch appropriate service providers). GPS location data collected for the purpose of providing Connect CARE services is only available and used by us upon our receipt of an automatic notification from your vehicle, when the SOS button is pushed or when you request other online roadside services through the “wrench” button.

Although Connect CARE is automatically activated in equipped vehicles, to utilize the Audi Service Request function of Connect CARE, you must register a “key user.”  The data collection practices around key user registration and Audi Service Request functionality are discussed in separate sections below.

We may use your information in a number of ways, including: 

  * to provide the products and services you have purchased or requested
  * to support your vehicle, products and services
  * to communicate with you about your vehicle, products or services
  * to diagnose, repair and track service and quality issues
  * to install and configure changes and updates to your services
  * to authenticate users of our products and services
  * to evaluate the performance and safety of our vehicles, products and services
  * to improve the quality of our vehicles, products and services
  * to operate the AoA website and digital properties and customize the content
  * to verify your eligibility for certain programs or benefits
  * to comply with legal requirements
  * to protect the safety, property or rights of AoA, owners, registered users, drivers, passengers or others
  * to prevent and detect fraud or misuse of the vehicles, products or services
  * to maintain internal records
  * for marketing purposes

We use the information provided in association with an Audi Service Request to evaluate your service needs and remind you to schedule a service appointment as indicated in your contact preferences. Your contact preferences may include a preferred Audi Dealer or service center. Prior to the time your car reaches a recommended service interval, it will send mileage and warning indicators, if any, to AoA, and if you have named a preferred Audi Dealer in your contact preferences, your preferred Audi Dealer. An Audi service representative may contact you via phone, email or letter to schedule a service appointment.  Your preferred Audi Dealer may also contact you via phone, email or letter to schedule a service appointment, and can also access this data for the purpose of preparing for and executing the service appointment.

We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner. 

To opt-out of receiving promotional email messages from us, please click on the "Unsubscribe" link contained at the bottom of each email.

We may share your information (a) within the Volkswagen Group family of companies, which includes parents, corporate affiliates, subsidiaries, business units and other companies that share common ownership, including Audi AG; (b) with third-party service providers working on behalf of AoA (such as advertising agencies and other third parties that provide marketing services, marketing research, and other analytics for marketing purposes) and third party content providers; and (c) Audi Dealers for sales, leasing, and customer service purposes, such as responding to quote requests, vehicle diagnosis, maintenance and repair, scheduling service appointments, and contacting you and providing the requested services. Some of our service providers, including Audi AG, are located outside of the United States.

We also share your information with emergency responders and service providers (such as police, ambulance providers, and towing providers) and law enforcement for purposes of offering Connect CARE.

We also share information with your vehicle’s satellite radio and/or wireless service provider, if applicable, to enable those service providers to contact you with important information about your vehicle’s satellite or wireless services and for their own marketing purposes. 

With your express permission, we also will share your information with selected third parties you choose, to enable services that use your information but are not provided directly by Audi. These services could include, but are not limited to, remote package and fuel delivery, or usage-based insurance or tolling pricing, or other mobility-based services.

In addition, we may share your information with third parties, law enforcement or other government agencies to comply with law or legal requirements; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements; and to protect our rights and the property or safety of our users or third-parties. We also may disclose information about you and your Vehicle when we have reason to believe that someone is causing injury to or interference with our rights or property, other users of the websites or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities.

If we or some or all of our assets are acquired by another company, including through a sale in connection with bankruptcy, we will share the information that we hold with that company.

We also share your information with other carefully selected companies with whom we may partner to provide you with information about products or services we think may be of interest to you.  We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

##### _Online Advertising_

To provide you with a more relevant and interesting experience, Audi may work with third party companies to display ads or customize the content of the Audi digital properties.  These companies may use cookies (a small text file), pixels, tags, or similar technologies that are placed in browsers to gather information about your visits to an Audi digital property, as well as your visits elsewhere on the Internet.  These companies use this information to provide you with more relevant advertising known as interest-based advertising. Some of these companies may be participants in the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA"). The DAA offers a choice mechanism with respect to certain types of data collection and use. We adhere to the DAA’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. Visit _[www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/)_ to exercise choice with respect to participants of the DAA or click on the AboutAds icon on an AoA advertisement and follow the instructions on how to opt out. If you change computers, devices, or browsers, use multiple computers, devices, or browsers, or delete your cookies, you may need to repeat this process for each computer, device, or browser. Opting out of interest-based advertising will not opt you out of all advertising, but rather only interest-based advertising from AoA or its agents or representatives.

To opt-out of receiving promotional email messages from us, please click on the "Unsubscribe" link contained at the bottom of each email.

The AoA websites also collect information, via cookies, web beacons, pixels, tags or other tracking technologies, such as your Internet Service Provider and IP address, the date and time you access the AoA website, the pages you have accessed while visiting the AoA website, and the Internet address from which you accessed the AoA website. Some cookies exist only during a single session and some are persistent over multiple sessions over time.  We use these technologies to remember user preferences, maximize the performance of our website and services, provide you with offers that may be of interest to you, measure the effectiveness of our email campaigns and to personalize online content.

Some browsers have incorporated Do Not Track (“DNT”) preferences. Most of these features, when turned on, send signals to the website you are visiting that you do not wish to have information about your online searching and browsing activities collected and used.  As there is not yet a common agreement about how to interpret DNT signals, we do not honor DNT signals from website browsers at this time.  However, you may refuse or delete cookies.  If you refuse or delete cookies, some of our website functionality may be impaired.  Please refer to your browser’s Help instructions to learn more about how to manage cookies and the use of other tracking technologies. 

In addition to mobile applications designed to allow you to use your myAudi, Audi connect or Audi connect e-tron services, AoA may have mobile applications that you can download to your mobile device or vehicle (“AoA Applications”). When you download an AoA Application, there may be an opportunity for you to provide us with or for us to obtain information about you or your vehicle. Each AoA Application will display a separate Privacy Statement that will inform you about how any new or different information shared via the application will be handled.  Otherwise, information collected via Audi mobile applications will be the information identified above and will be used and shared as stated in this Privacy Statement.

 Through the Infotainment system, AoA may also offer applications developed by third parties (“3rd Party Application”). When you download a 3rd Party Application to your mobile device or vehicle, the 3rd Party Application may collect information about you or your vehicle in connection with your download or use of that application. AoA is not responsible for the collection or use of information by 3rd Party Applications. We recommend that you carefully review the privacy statement of each 3rd Party Application prior to downloading or using them.

AoA does not knowingly collect information from visitors under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.  For questions or additional information, see “Contact Us” section below.

The AoA websites may contain links to other websites, including social networks, advertisers, Audi Dealer websites, Audi Financial Services websites, other Volkswagen Group websites, including websites operated by Audi AG, and websites belonging to other third parties. Some of these sites may share a similar “look and feel” to the AoA websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements provided by other websites before you provide information to them.

AoA maintains reasonable safeguards to protect your information.  Some services, including Audi connect services, may involve the transmission of voice and data from your Audi vehicle over wireless and cellular telephone networks and therefore, we cannot guarantee the privacy and security of conversations or data transmitted to and from your Audi vehicle.

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Statement by updating this page and by displaying the date of the last update at the top of the page. We encourage you periodically to check this site to learn about the information we collect, use, and share. Your continued use of any of the AoA websites, products or services affirms your agreement to such changes.

If you are a California resident you have the right to request information from AoA regarding the manner in which AoA shares certain categories of your personal information with third parties for the third parties direct marketing purposes. California law provides that you have the right to submit a request to AoA at its designated address and receive the following information:

  * the categories of information AoA disclosed to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year; and
  * the names and addresses of third parties that received such information, or if the nature of their business cannot be determined from the name, then examples of the products or services marketed.

You are entitled to receive a copy of this information in a standardized format and the information will not be specific to you individually. You may make such a request by emailing  _[auditalk@audi.com](mailto:auditalk@audi.com)_ or by contacting us via the contact information below. 

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement, please email us at: [auditalk@audi.com](mailto:auditalk@audi.com).

You may also contact us by phone, 24 hours a day, at: 1-800-822-AUDI.

And by mail at:

Audi Customer Experience Center  
3800 Hamlin Road  
Auburn Hills, MI 48326

##### **If You Create a myAudi Account**

You can choose to create a myAudi account to access and use AoA personalized services, applications and programs relating to your vehicle.  In addition to the information practices described in the AoA Full Privacy Statement, this statement describes how we collect, use and share your information during registration and use of your myAudi account and the applications, program and services available through myAudi.  You can create a myAudi account without choosing to use Audi connect services.  If you also choose to utilize Audi connect services, we have provided additional information below about information collection, use and sharing for those services.  In addition, you may choose to access your Audi Financial Services (AFS) account through your myAudi portal.  If you do so, the details of your financial transactions (e.g. account balance, automatic payments, bank account information) will not be shared with Audi, its affiliated entities or the third parties identified in this Privacy Statement. Such information will be used strictly in accordance with the AFS Privacy Statement available **_[here](https://www.audifs.com/Public/PrivacyPolicy)_**.  Information shared between Audi and AFS will be limited to general vehicle purchase information such as VIN, make, model, year, dealer, date of purchase or lease, purchase/lease price, vehicle equipment, and service history—even if you choose to access your AFS account through your myAudi portal.

In addition to the general information identified above, we collect the information that you provide in your myAudi account in the course of or subsequent to registration and verification. This includes:

  * data that you provide when setting up a myAudi Account, such as first and last name, VIN, email and mailing address, gender, salutation, place of residence, telephone and mobile number, preferred language, usernames and passwords
  * data regarding your personalized settings for your Audi connect services accessed through you myAudi account, such as preferred Audi partners, preferences for using e-mail, mailing address or text messages for sending service or application function notifications, vehicle catalogues, newsletter or other direct communications 
  * additional data you choose to share to help tailor your myAudi account content and services

In addition to the uses identified above, we use the information provided through your myAudi account registration and use to: activate the account; allow you to access your myAudi account; allow you to use the available applications, services and programs available through your myAudi account; perform desired customer services; and maintain information relevant to your myAudi account. We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

You can register an Audi vehicle in your myAudi account by entering and saving your vehicle identification number (“VIN”). The VIN is required to access and use certain applications in your vehicle and to use the vehicle management application in your myAudi account.  By using the vehicle management application, your vehicle's equipment details can be automatically populated by entering your vehicle identification number.

The data you enter into your myAudi account are saved and made available to your registered vehicle on demand. We save the data until you delete it from your myAudi Account or you delete your myAudi Account. 

##### **If You Choose to Use Audi connect Services**

YYou can choose to use your myAudi account to access and use available Audi connect services, which include Connect PRIME and Connect PLUS (Connect CARE is automatically provided).  Certain vehicles may be equipped with Audi Connect CARE which does not require any action from you to activate and is automatically enabled and active before purchase or lease. Connect CARE data collection and use practices were discussed above.  If you activate a free trial or paid subscription to Audi connect services, additional information will be collected.  In addition to the information identified in the full AoA Privacy Statement above, we collect, use, and share information about you and your registered Audi vehicle during your free trial or paid subscription services available through Audi connect.  Some Audi connect vehicles are not equipped to offer all of the Audi connect services mentioned in this Privacy Statement.  To find out what services are available in your vehicle, see www.audiusa.com/audiconnect.

The Audi connect services include offerings from various third-party content providers, such as Google, Twitter, etc. (“Content Provider”).  AoA does not create or control the content offered by these Content Providers.  The Content Providers are exclusively responsible for the content and the availability of the content accessible through Audi connect.  However, AoA does collect and share certain information with these Content Providers in order for you to receive the content requested.  For a complete list of the Audi connect Content Providers and their respective contact information, please see “Content Providers” below.

For complete Audi connect Terms of Service please _[click here](https://www.audiusa.com/content/dam/audiusa/Innovation/Intelligence/Intelligence_Audi_Connect/Audi_connect_ToS_Jan_4_2016.pdf)_

Please note that through Audi connect services, including Connect PLUS, you can purchase additional services or offerings from us or other third parties.  Certain services or offerings from third parties will be subject to their Terms of Service and Privacy Statement, not ours.  This includes Wi-Fi hotspot service, provided by a wireless carrier that contracts directly with you.  In the course of providing wireless services, the provider may collect information about you, your Audi vehicle, and your use of Audi connect services, including information that allows the provider to determine the location of your vehicle.  The provider’s collection, use, and sharing of the information it collects is governed by its own privacy policy, not ours.  You should read the privacy policy that your wireless provider has made available to you because the provider’s practices may differ from ours.  If you are not the subscriber for this vehicle’s Audi connect services, you should ask the vehicle’s subscriber to tell you about any third party providers contracting directly with the subscriber, including which carrier is providing this vehicle’s wireless services.

In addition to the general information from and about you or your vehicle identified in the full AoA Privacy Statement and myAudi information above, when you set up and use Audi connect services, additional information will be collected, including:

  * account information, such as billing, settings, personalized services and authentication information
  * information that you provide when using the Audi connect services, including information you send and information you request
  * information about your use of Audi connect services, vehicles equipped with Audi connect services, the Audi connect mobile application, and the Audi connect website
  * information about your interactions with us, our affiliates, or our Service or Content Providers
  * _GPS location data for services, such as Geofence, Map Update, Parking Position, Speed Alert, Valet Alert, Traffic Information, Local Hazard Alerts, Weather, and Travel Destinations_
  * **_driving behavior information for services, such as speed for Speed Alert, Local Hazard Alert, Online Traffic Signs, and Valet Alert_**
  * **_voice command data (including any personal data included therein) combined with GPS location data, for the purpose of providing the requested service and to improve the voice command capabilities_**

If you set up and use Audi connect services, and your car is equipped with online voice command, you will be provided an opportunity in your vehicle to acknowledge and accept these conditions before the online "voice command" function can be used.

Please note that the information stored in your Audi vehicle may be accessible to others who use your Audi vehicle or mobile device, and thus may be deleted, altered, or transferred.  Please see your vehicle’s owner’s manual for information about how to remove the information stored in your Audi vehicle.

We do not store the content of any messages (such as social media messages) that you transmit or access through Audi connect and we do not access or retain information about the locations associated with any information requests (such as information feeds, travel information) that you submit through Audi connect, other than information requests for location based services.

In addition to the entities identified in the full AoA Privacy Statement above, we share information collected through use of Audi connect services with the third-party Content Providers identified below.  Information about how Content Providers use and share information associated with your use of Audi connect services is available at the Content Providers’ websites. 

The following is a list of the current Audi connect Content Providers and their respective websites and contact information. This list is subject to change without notice.

_Content Providers_

At present, the following third-party Content Providers offer services via Audi connect:

  * point-of-interest searching (POI), including voice control, navigation with Google Earth images : Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA – www.google.com
  * Twitter: Twitter Inc. 795 Folsom Street, Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA – www.twitter.com
  * news: www.afp.com, www.npr.com and any other RSS feed providers that you may choose to add;
  * city events: Wcities.com, Inc., 512 2nd Street Second Floor, San Francisco , CA 94107, USA – www.wcities.com;
  * traffic information: INRIX Inc., 10210 NE Points Drive, Suite 300, Kirkland, WA 98033, USA – www.inrix.com in addition to: HERE Global B.V., Kennedyplein 222 -226, 5611 ZT Eindhoven, The Netherlands
  * parking information: Parkopedia Limited,  232 Sladepool Farm Road, Birmingham, West Midlands, B14 5EE – [www.parkopedia.com](http://www.parkopedia.com/)
  * fuel price information: OPISNAVX c/o IHS,
  * 18 rue du Quatre Septembre, 75002 Paris, France - www.opisnavx.com/
  * flight information: FlightStats, Inc., 522 SW 5th Avenue, Suite 200, Portland, OR 97204, USA – www.flightstats-inc.com __
  * _traffic light information: Traffic Technology Services, Inc., 17933 NW Evergreen Pkwy #240, Beaverton, OR 97006 –_[www.traffictechservices.com](http://www.traffictechservices.com/) __
  * weather:  MeteoGroup Ltd., 292 Vauxhall Bridge Road, London SW1V 1AE - www.meteogroup.com 

In addition to the general purposes described above, we use the information generated in association with your use of Audi connect to process your specific requests for Audi connect services. 

We use the information provided to register a Key User and Authorized Users to authenticate the users and provide them with requested Audi connect services.

We may also use or share your information in an anonymized or aggregate manner.

##### **If You Choose to Register a Key User**

You must register a “Key User” to access and use certain Connect CARE services, such as Audi Service Requests, and certain Connect PRIME services, such as Curfew Alerts, Geofencing Alerts, Speed Alerts, Valet Alerts, Remote Lock & Unlock, Parking Position, and Vehicle Status Report.  You can also register other “Authorized Users” to allow them to access and use some of these Audi connect services.

Designating and activating a Key User or Authorized User requires the collection of additional information about those users, including:

  * name
  * date of birth
  * email address
  * login credential and PIN

At the time of Key User Registration, the “Audi Service Request” function is activated as part of Connect CARE.  We use the information provided in association with an Audi Service Request to evaluate your service needs and remind you to schedule a service appointment as indicated in your contact preferences. Your contact preferences may include a preferred Audi Dealer or service center. Prior to the time your car reaches a recommended service interval, it will send mileage, warning indicators, and other service-relevant data, to AoA, and if you have named a preferred Audi Dealer in your contact preferences, your preferred Audi Dealer. An Audi service representative may contact you via phone, email or letter to schedule a service appointment.  Your preferred Audi Dealer may also contact you via phone, email or letter to schedule a service appointment, and can also access this data for the purpose of preparing for and executing the service appointment.

To opt-out of the Audi Service Request feature, please log in to your myAudi account.

##### **If You Use Audi A3 e-tron connect Services**

_[Click here](https://etron.audiusa.com/web/aucwp/privacy-policy)_ to link to the Audi e-tron connect Privacy Statement.
